<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rizwan Khan👨🏻‍💻</title>
    <link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rizwan Khan👨🏻‍💻</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 11:16:23 +0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rizwan-kh.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>(Azure DevOps) Send Json Request(Parameters) to Azure Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2021/06/azure-devops-send-json-requestparameters-to-azure-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 11:16:23 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2021/06/azure-devops-send-json-requestparameters-to-azure-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>Introduction If you&amp;rsquo;ve been using Azure DevOps, you would know that a pipeline can be trigger with runtime parameters in the format key: value pair and this is great for doing almost all of the tasks.
For our use-case, we had been looking at option to send a JSON based parameter dictionary and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any way at the time of writing this article. We came up with a hack to achieve this and I would want to write it up in this blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am Rizwan Khan;</title>
      <link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 16:44:33 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>welcome to my page - I am from Kolkata, a city in India. I grew up in a joint family. I graduated from the West Bengal University of Technology with a major in Information Technology and most part of my education was completed in the same city.
I started my career with CMC Limited in Mumbai and used to work on C++ and C for a major Stock Exchange as a Backend Developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo &amp; GitHub - Setup Static Website on GitHub</title>
      <link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/06/hugo-github-setup-static-website-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 22:32:01 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/06/hugo-github-setup-static-website-on-github/</guid>
      <description>Hugo and Github Account A small write-up on how this site was setup. There are plenty of materials available all over the internet, but this is more of a self-help document for myself to refer back in future to understand how this was all setup.
 Hugo can be downloaded from their official release page A GitHub account needs to be created from this link and a public repo is required to be setup here  After installing Hugo, to generate a new site, run the below command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klar</title>
      <link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/03/klar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 17:20:26 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/03/klar/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Klar is a static binary tool to analyze images stored in a private or public Docker registry for security vulnerabilities using Clair. Klar is designed to be used as an integration tool so it relies on environment variables. It&amp;rsquo;s a single binary which requires no dependencies and can be plugged and/or integrated into our CI CD pipelines.
Klar serves as a client which coordinates the image checks between the Docker registry and Clair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/03/vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 17:20:26 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/03/vagrant/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  Getting started with Vagrant Download the install the Vagrant from the Download section
vagrant version Installed Version: 2.2.10 Latest Version: 2.2.10 You&#39;re running an up-to-date version of Vagrant! Download and install VirtualBox
Now if both Vagrant and VirtualBox are up and running, all we need to do is run the below 3 commands to have a Ubuntu VM up and available for our use in no time.
vagrant init hashicorp/bionic64 vagrant up vagrant ssh This is a pretty simple way to spin up a new Ubuntu VM, we can do a lot more which I will try to write up in later posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gitlab CI &amp; Kaniko to build Docker Images</title>
      <link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/02/gitlab-ci-kaniko-to-build-docker-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 12:11:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/02/gitlab-ci-kaniko-to-build-docker-images/</guid>
      <description>Introduction You can build container images from a Dockerfile inside a container or a Kubernetes cluster, though Jérôme Petazzoni strongly discourages from doing so. He wrote a detailed blog that can be read here on why not to build container images using Dockerfile inside a container or a Kubernetes cluster.
 Context You will get N number of blogs on how to use the CI/CD of GitLab; here we will see an easy reference point to extend a file and create CI/CD for Docker Image to be built and stored in the same GitLab registry using kaniko.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use service accounts for Kubernetes imagePullSecrets</title>
      <link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/01/how-to-use-service-accounts-for-kubernetes-imagepullsecrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 17:40:27 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/01/how-to-use-service-accounts-for-kubernetes-imagepullsecrets/</guid>
      <description>What are Service Accounts in Kubernetes? As per Kubernetes.io - A service account provides an identity for processes that run in a Pod.
One can think of service accounts as service users for pods. They help pods authenticate with the api-server and interact with it.
 Many times, we come across a situation where our organization uses a private Docker registry to store the Docker images and to make this available we need to create a docker-registry kubernetes secret and pass as imagePullSecrets in the deployment manifest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2019/10/docker-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 05:11:13 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2019/10/docker-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>Below are few of the main and basic commands used in Docker, an easy pick-up and good-to-go command page for docker troubleshooting.
Alias  If you are a lazy developer/sysadmin like me, the first thing you should do on your system is to make easy alias of all the long commands, below are the ones I often use on any system I use on a daily basis:
These can be imported on ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tmux</title>
      <link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2019/06/tmux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 21:53:35 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2019/06/tmux/</guid>
      <description>tmux - Terminal Multiplexer tmux is a terminal multiplexer. It helps switch between multiple programs in one terminal, detach them(they keep running in background) and reattach when needed. I started using tmux as someone recommended me to start using it as it helps with CKA &amp;amp; CKAD (which I have still not attempted) and then later on I was heavily using it for my website(with Hugo). I had previously used mPutty, but mPutty uses mutliple logged in sessions to display on screen, whereas tmux simply multiply the existing sessions on screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May the force be with you!</title>
      <link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/archieve/blank/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2010 11:11:11 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/archieve/blank/</guid>
      <description>I am groot! </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>