<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rizwan Khan👨🏻‍💻</title><link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Rizwan Khan👨🏻‍💻</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 19:31:58 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rizwan-kh.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hashicorp Vault &amp; Azure AD Identity Integration</title><link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2022/02/hashicorp-vault-azure-ad-identity-integration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 19:31:58 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2022/02/hashicorp-vault-azure-ad-identity-integration/</guid><description>Introduction In this post, we will be implementing Hashicorp Vault authentication with Microsoft Azure AD as an identity provider using OIDC(OpenID Connect). The default token authentication is always enabled.
Configuration There are two configurations that we had to do to achieve this with Azure AD, one is for app registration in the Azure Portal and the other one is on Vault - enabling the OIDC based auth. Steps for both are described below.</description></item><item><title>Integration of Azure AD as OIDC identity provider for AWS EKS</title><link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2021/12/integration-of-azure-ad-as-oidc-identity-provider-for-aws-eks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 23:40:21 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2021/12/integration-of-azure-ad-as-oidc-identity-provider-for-aws-eks/</guid><description>Introduction In my project we are using many flavours of Kubernetes viz. EKS, AKS, GKE, RKE, ACK. RBAC for all these cluster are managed via a central Active Directory as well as the user authentication, and this is achieved centrally by onboarding all the cluster on Rancher to manage all Kubernetes cluster.
I had a requirement where we couldn&amp;rsquo;t onboard the users to our Active Directory, and the plan was to give them access to Amazon EKS via an Azure AD external users(or guest users).</description></item><item><title>Trivy - Scan Container Images</title><link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2021/12/trivy-scan-container-images/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 23:10:21 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2021/12/trivy-scan-container-images/</guid><description>Trivy Trivy is a scanner for vulnerabilities in container images, file systems, git repositories and configuration. It&amp;rsquo;s an Aqua Security open source project that can be easily used to integrate with our existing CI CD pipeline or used as an stand alone tool to scan container images deployed on Kubernetes cluster.
We were using Clair previous to our switch to Trivy as we analyzed both the tools and found Trivy to be more helpful for the longer run - it was faster, had more CVE database updates as compared to Clair and didn&amp;rsquo;t depend on external clients to interact/scan.</description></item><item><title>Traefik on Kubernetes with Let's Encrypt &amp; Route53</title><link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2021/07/traefik-on-kubernetes-with-lets-encrypt-route53/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 17:40:27 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2021/07/traefik-on-kubernetes-with-lets-encrypt-route53/</guid><description>Why Traefik? Traefik is a modern dynamic load balancer and reverse proxy, its easy to setup, control and provides lots of options which sits right with our use-cases. It integrates with Lets Encrypt to provide SSL termination along with support for service discovery, tracing, metrics out of the box running on Kubernetes as a small pod.
Since when We have been using Traefik since early 2017 on 2 of our cluster as a daemonset Kubernetes object with externalDNS to update the worker nodes IP with our DNS provider and used to manually generate and update Lets Encrypt certificate on a Kubernetes secret object.</description></item><item><title>(Azure DevOps) Send Json Request(Parameters) to Azure Pipelines</title><link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2021/06/azure-devops-send-json-requestparameters-to-azure-pipelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 11:16:23 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2021/06/azure-devops-send-json-requestparameters-to-azure-pipelines/</guid><description>Introduction If you&amp;rsquo;ve been using Azure DevOps, you would know that a pipeline can be trigger with runtime parameters in the format key: value pair and this is great for doing almost all of the tasks.
For our use-case, we had been looking at option to send a JSON based parameter dictionary and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any way at the time of writing this article. We came up with a hack to achieve this and I would want to write it up in this blog post.</description></item><item><title>I am Rizwan Khan;</title><link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 16:44:33 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/about/</guid><description>welcome to my page - I am from Kolkata, a city in India. I grew up in a joint family. I graduated from the West Bengal University of Technology with a major in Information Technology and most part of my education was completed in the same city.
I started my career with CMC Limited in Mumbai and used to work on C++ and C for a major Stock Exchange as a Backend Developer.</description></item><item><title>Hugo &amp; GitHub - Setup Static Website on GitHub</title><link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/06/hugo-github-setup-static-website-on-github/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 22:32:01 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/06/hugo-github-setup-static-website-on-github/</guid><description>Hugo and Github Account A small write-up on how this site was setup. There are plenty of materials available all over the internet, but this is more of a self-help document for myself to refer back in future to understand how this was all setup.
Hugo can be downloaded from their official release page A GitHub account needs to be created from this link and a public repo is required to be setup here After installing Hugo, to generate a new site, run the below command:</description></item><item><title>Klar</title><link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/03/klar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 17:20:26 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/03/klar/</guid><description>Introduction Klar is a static binary tool to analyze images stored in a private or public Docker registry for security vulnerabilities using Clair. Klar is designed to be used as an integration tool so it relies on environment variables. It&amp;rsquo;s a single binary which requires no dependencies and can be plugged and/or integrated into our CI CD pipelines.
Klar serves as a client which coordinates the image checks between the Docker registry and Clair.</description></item><item><title>Vagrant</title><link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/03/vagrant/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 17:20:26 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/03/vagrant/</guid><description>Introduction Getting started with Vagrant Download the install the Vagrant from the Download section
vagrant version Installed Version: 2.2.10 Latest Version: 2.2.10 You're running an up-to-date version of Vagrant! Download and install VirtualBox
Now if both Vagrant and VirtualBox are up and running, all we need to do is run the below 3 commands to have a Ubuntu VM up and available for our use in no time.
vagrant init hashicorp/bionic64 vagrant up vagrant ssh This is a pretty simple way to spin up a new Ubuntu VM, we can do a lot more which I will try to write up in later posts.</description></item><item><title>Gitlab CI &amp; Kaniko to build Docker Images</title><link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/02/gitlab-ci-kaniko-to-build-docker-images/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 12:11:00 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2020/02/gitlab-ci-kaniko-to-build-docker-images/</guid><description>Introduction You can build container images from a Dockerfile inside a container or a Kubernetes cluster, though Jérôme Petazzoni strongly discourages from doing so. He wrote a detailed blog that can be read here on why not to build container images using Dockerfile inside a container or a Kubernetes cluster.
Context You will get N number of blogs on how to use the CI/CD of GitLab; here we will see an easy reference point to extend a file and create CI/CD for Docker Image to be built and stored in the same GitLab registry using kaniko.</description></item></channel></rss>