<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux on Rizwan Khan👨🏻‍💻</title><link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in linux on Rizwan Khan👨🏻‍💻</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 12:30:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rizwan-kh.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>(Linux) Debug Shell Scripts</title><link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2018/05/linux-debug-shell-scripts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 12:30:00 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2018/05/linux-debug-shell-scripts/</guid><description>Debug Shell Scripts In my experience, people when they want to debug a shell script, they usually use the set +xv and all this does is print each operation on the console output.
I found a better way to debug the shell script, which is consistent with going over each line on the press of the enter key
Simply add the below line in front of the place from where you want to start the debug</description></item><item><title>(Linux) Extract Public Key &amp; Fingerprint from Private</title><link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2018/03/linux-extract-public-key-fingerprint-from-private/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:28:21 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2018/03/linux-extract-public-key-fingerprint-from-private/</guid><description>Extract Public Key and Fingerprint from Private Key When managing SSH keys, you may need to extract the public key or obtain the fingerprint of a private key. Below are the commands to accomplish these tasks.
Get the Public Key To extract the public key from a private key file, use the following command:
ssh-keygen -f keyname -y Replace keyname with the path to your private key file.
Get the Fingerprint SHA-1 Fingerprint Convert the private key to DER format and compute the SHA-1 fingerprint:</description></item><item><title>(Linux) Remove systemd process</title><link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2018/03/linux-remove-systemd-process/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:28:21 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2018/03/linux-remove-systemd-process/</guid><description>Removing a systemd process from your Linux machine The below steps are to be performed to remove a systemd process
View the service unit file systemctl cat [servicename] Stop and disable the service systemctl stop [servicename] systemctl disable [servicename] Remove the service file rm /etc/systemd/system/[servicename] rm /etc/systemd/system/[servicename] #symlinks that might be related Reload systemd configuration systemctl daemon-reload Reset the failed systemd service systemctl reset-failed</description></item><item><title>(Linux) Convert pem to ppk</title><link>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2018/02/linux-convert-pem-to-ppk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:28:21 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://rizwan-kh.github.io/posts/2018/02/linux-convert-pem-to-ppk/</guid><description>Convert PEM to PPK &amp;amp; PPK to PEM If you&amp;rsquo;re using AWS EC2, you may need to convert PPK to PEM (or vice versa) when trying to SSH from different operating systems. Below are instructions on how to perform these conversions using the puttygen tool.
Convert PPK to PEM Install puttygen:
On Linux: You can install putty-tools using your package manager. For example, on Debian-based systems, run: sudo apt-get install putty-tools On Windows: Download and install PuTTY from the official website.</description></item></channel></rss>